# ALI NEHME, Ph.D.

# Full Stack Developer

GitHub:www.github.com/nehmea **+**1 438 334-1206 @ LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/ali-nehme1 Brossard, Canada

### SUMMARY

A Full Stack Developer with a passion for developing scalable and complex applications. Backed up with data science experience and a diverse set of soft skills from 10 years of scientific research. Always strive to bring 100% to the work I do. I look forward to joining a creative and hard-working team where I can grow my skills while pushing projects to success.

### **SELECTED PROJECTS**

#### ChatApp

**#** 09/2022

https://github.com/nehmea/2022-WDII-chatApp

A messaging app/forum similar to Discord with rooms and live messaging.

- Frontend: React.js and CSS / Backend: Node.js and socket.io / Database: MySQL
- Role: authorization, live messaging, database management, profile management

#### Commons

**1** 08/2022

https://github.com/SpicyRiceTea/HomingPigeonWD1

A website that can serve as a platform for people to share their possessions.

- Frontend: Thymeleaf, Bootstrap / Backend: Java Spring Boot / Database: MySQL
- Role: project skeleton, database management, authentication and authorization

### HomingPigeon

₩ 06/2022

https://github.com/SpicyRiceTea/HomingPigeonWD1

A commercial website for selling postcards.

- Frontend: PHP, HTML, and CSS / Backend: PHP / Database: PhPMyAdmin
- Role: products page (add to favourites & cart), product info, profile management

#### **Bookstore Library**

**#** 05/2022

https://github.com/nehmea/JAC\_FSD\_WS\_Bookstore

A REST API that stores information on books and users, and represent them to users.

- Frontend: JS, HTML, & CSS / Backend: Java Spring Boot / Database: MySQL
- Role: I developed the whole API (solo project)

# PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

### **Principal Mentor**

STEM-Away

₩ 06/2020 - Ongoing USA (Remote)

· Designed workshops and oversaw educative projects in bioinformatics

# Computational Biology Consultant

## 09/2019 - Ongoing

· Helped private and academic teams design projects and perform analysis.

# Postdoctoral Researcher in Cancer Genomics

McGill University

**1** 09/2018 - 08/2020 Montreal, Canada

- Designed a workflow to analyze spatial transcriptomics data.
- Assisted colleagues and collaborators on eight projects with bioinformatics analysis on RNA-seq, scRNA-seq, and GeoMx DSP data.

# Postdoctoral Researcher in Molecular and Computational Biology

**University of Tours** 

Intermediate • • • • •

- · Designed a workflow for horizontal integration of transcriptomics datasets.
- Delivered results on 12 projects using computational and bench methods.
- Initiated a project for biomarkers discovery and prognostic score development in AML using data science and machine learning models.

French

# LANGUAGES

Proficient •••• **English Arabic** Native •

**1** 09/2016 - 06/2018 Tours, France

# Masters in Genomics and Health

Lebanese University

**1** 09/2010 - 06/2012

# TRAINING / WORKSHOPS

The Data Science Course 2022: Complete Data Science Bootcamp

Udemy, Ongoing

Introduction to the Unix Shell

Calcul Quebec, September 2020

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS** Frameworks

Java Spring Boot ASP.NET **WPF** Razor Pages jQuery

.NET core

Socket IO

#### Frontend

React

JavaScript XAML **HTML** CSS

ThymeLeaf

#### Backend

Java NodeJS PHP Python C#

# Database

MySQL MSSQL PhPMyAdmin

# Hosting

AWS EC2 **AWS RDS XAMPP** 

# Project Management

Github Microsoft Office Trello

# Data Science

**Data Wrangling** Visualization Regression

SOFT SKILLS

Agile Time management **Teamwork** Presentation Self-learning Flexiblity

# **EDUCATION**

### Full-Stack Developer (AEC, 1035 hours)

John Abbott's College

## 01/2022 - Ongoing

# Ph.D. in Bioinformatics and Pathophysiology Claude Bernard University Lyon 1

**11/2015 11/2015**